Name: Kaizhao Zhang

Gender: Male

Birthplace: Puning city, Guangdong province, China Residence: Guangzhou city, Guangdong province, China

Mobile: 086-13502460825

E-mail: zhangkaizhao@gmail.com

Job objective

Including but not limited to: Developer Engineer, Senior Development Engineer Including but not limited to: Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Shantou, Jieyang, Puning

Summary

Graduated from the South China University of Technology in Mechanical Engineering and Automation in 2005. As a mechanical engineer especially equipment engineer for about three years. Then begin to be a computer programmer in 2008. Mainly using Python language in web development(front end, back end), skilled working in GNU/Linux distribution environment.

Work experience

- 2014,06 ~ 2014,12: Guangdong Caihui Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou) Senior Development Engineer

Working on development of internet lottery purcharsing agent system.

Using Python language. Using Flask/SQLAlchemy, etc.

- May,2011 - Jan,2014: Guangzhou Farcloud Network Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou)

Development Engineer

Early days, working on development(generating and accessing the preview and thumbnails images and metadata of various files including image files/PDF files/Office files/audio files/video files/text files. pushing files to Dropbox/Google Drive/SkyDrive/Jinshan Kuaipan/Kanbox. etc.) and maintenance(service API, etc.) of Syncbox webserver, maintenance of Syncbox Client for Linux, and maintenance of related DDNS server and client. etc.

Later period, as the author of public web application for WIT-FII Router(Account/Router management, service API, web gateway service, online shop(including the integration of Alipay create_direct_pay_by_user payment API), etc), and the developer of Desktop Client for WIT-FII Router, etc. (Note: WIT-FII Router product has not been published to public yet.)

Using Python language. Early days using Tornado/Kyoto Cabinet/Berkeley DB, etc. Later period using gevent/WebOb/Jinja2/WTForms/SQLAlchemy/Redis/PyQt5, etc.

May, 2010 - May, 2011: Guangzhou G4B Technologies Co., Ltd. (Guangzhou)
 Development Engineer

Working on autoupdate server developement. File synchronization server and client prototype development. Ubuntu Server and other work related software management.

Using Python language.

Sep,2008 - Dec,2009: Zopen Technologies Co.,Ltd. (Guangzhou)
 Development Engineer

Working on front-end and back-end development of everydo products. Ubuntu server deployment, etc.

Using Python language and Zope 3, etc.

- Apr, 2006 - Jul, 2008: Shantou Goworld Display Co., Ltd. (Shantou)

Apr,2006 - Jul,2008: Shantou Goworld Display Co.,Ltd. (Shantou)
 Equipment Engineer

Production machines maintenance. Design and repair fixtures of the machines, etc.

Using repair tools and AutoCAD/SolidWorks design tools, etc.

Education

- Sep,2001 Jul,2005: South China University of Technology Bachelor of engineering Mechanical Engineering and Automatizaion
- Sep,1998 Jul,2001: Shantou Jinshan School Senior high school
- Sep,1995 Jul,1998: Puning Hongye School Junior high school

Skills

- Python language and Python standard library, third party libraries, web frameworks and servers
- GNU/Linux. e.g. Debian/Ubuntu, Fedora, Arch Linux, Gentoo, etc
- Vim
- Git
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, etc

Links

_ _ _ _ _

Working related

- http://www.clt500.com
- https://www.witfii.com/index.html
- http://www.isyncbox.com
- http://www.everydo.com
- ...

Personal related

- https://bitbucket.org/zhangkaizhao
- https://github.com/metalman
- http://www.douban.com/people/halfcool/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhangkaizhao

_ _

Last modified on Apr.30,2015